Please <u>save</u> or <u>view</u> the most recent version of my résumé, hosted on Microsoft Github.

I am a data scientist with 4 years of creating and working with data science applications: data preparation, data models, dashboarding and analysis. Honoured with the Good Citizenship award by my high school peers and staff, I take great pride in the respect I have for people – I appreciate all opportunities to engage with others and improve their lives. To acquire a diverse world view, I follow articles, books and podcasts on data management, psychology and entrepreneurship. My passion for people, experiences, and ambitions have influenced my professional interests – to create operational, strategic and risk management frameworks for scalable ventures as I become a data scientist in consumer markets.

Education

2021-09 – 2022-09

Master of Real Estate Finance – in progress

Henley Business School, Reading, England

- Coursework on economics, securities, futures, options, fixed income & equity, funding, development processes & appraisals, valuation, and global markets & investment. All in the context of real estate
- Dissertation proposal on retail real estate

2019-02 – 2021-03

Master of Computer Science by Dissertation: Data Science – with distinction

University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, South Africa

 Dissertation on multivariate time series analysis, anomaly detection, natural language processing, metric design and forecasting

2018-02 – 2018-12

Bachelor of Science Honours: Big Data Analytics

University of the Witwatersrand

- Research report on algorithms for fraud detection
- Coursework in Statistics, Computer Vision, General Machine Learning, Optimisation, Data Analysis, Visualisation and Image Processing

2015-02 – 2017-12

Bachelor of Science: Economics and Mathematics

University of the Witwatersrand

 Coursework in Mathematics, Computer Science, Information Systems, Economics and Accounting,

Bill Seota

Personal Information

Phone

+27 84 381 7712

E-mail

bseota@gmail.com

LinkedIn

Bill Seota

Skills and Technical Applications

Please click the link below for the price optimisation dashboard:

Price Optimisation

Please click the link below for the company metrics dashboard:

EverSparc Dashboard

Please click the link below for my Github page:

<u>Github</u>

Public Speaking and Presentations

Python for data modelling, forecasting and visualisation

Python for Computer Vision

SQL

Python for Recommender Systems

Excel for valuation models

Git

Work History

2020-11 - Data and Investment Analyst

2021-06

Bopa Moruo Private Equity Fund Managers, Johannesburg Prepared financial reporting and operational dashboards for investor due-diligence and portfolio company reports. These dashboards entailed streamlining the financial reporting and visual analysis workflows to modelling operational efficiency within its portfolio companies provide investment appraisals to the investment team. This dashboard was the first of its kind and reduced reporting time from 17 weekly hours to 20 minutes.

2020-09 -2020-11

Customer Pricing Analyst

Tiger Consumer Brands Limited, Johannesburg

- Worked with the data scientist to prepare product category sales data.
- Uploaded and maintained the first ever profitability dashboard across the company. The dashboard:
 - 1. improved the quality and accuracy of reports, and
 - 2. reduced the reporting time from 20 weekly hours to 5 minutes.

2019-08 – 2020-06

Product Developer

Moya, Johannesburg

Moya's BlackBook was a fintech product to help small retail and service businesses obtain loans using transactions and macroeconomic data. As one of Moya's three founders, I was responsible for BlackBook's conception and its early phase production and developing relationships with merchants.

2019-10 – 2020-06

AlphaCode Explore Incubate Member

AlphaCode & Explore Data Science Academy, Johannesburg
I worked on business formulation and strategies around the
BlackBook fintech product, covering the following tasks:

- 1. Using data science to scale organisations
- 2. Business thinking for 10x ventures
- 3. Design thinking and design sprints
- 4. Prototyping and testing BlackBook with our clients

2019-06 – 2019-07

Technology Analyst

- J. P. MORGAN Corporate and Investment Bank, Johannesburg
- Trained by my line manager to understand the technology design and usage that ensures optimum transaction flow into, within and out of the Bank
- Consulted with the 12 other line managers (Corporate and Investment Banking, Equity Research, Finance, Treasury, Trading, Sales, Operations, Compliance, Technology Infrastructure, Client Onboarding, Business Management) on their integrations within the Bank, and completed three projects involving the Finance, Operations and Technology departments

2019-09 – Entrepreneur-In-Training

2019-12

Investec Startup School, Cape Town, South Africa

- Worked alongside mentors to expand my understanding of business models as well as internal and external drivers of an organisation
- Developed two business plans for my operationalinnovation ideas for small enterprises

2016-05 – Counsellor and Council Member 2018-12 Mathematical Science Student Council

Mathematical Science Student Council, University of the Witwatersrand

- I was tasked with helping students who needed academic planning and guidance
- As a council, we ensured the well-being of Science students regarding fair satisfactory performance criteria
- In 2016, I was of seven students from a voluntary committee that introduced supplementary lessons and supplementary examinations for second-year Mathematics modules – the pass rate improved by 70%

Certificates and Courses

2020-07	Yale University – Financial Markets
2020-07	Duke University – Startup Company Valuation Methods
2020-06	Udemy – Mergers & Acquisitions and Disinvestment
2020-04	Udemy – Company Valuation: Integrated Statements, Forecasting
2020-03	Udemy – Complete CFA Modules (Course)
2019-09	SAIIA EU-SA Youth for Climate Action Conference – Volunteering
2019-09	IBM Data Science Acceleration Course
2019-05	Huawei 5G Overview Training Course
2014-11	Good Citizenship Award – Cornwall Hill College (CHC)
2014-10	Public Speaking: Toastmasters, Senior Best Speaker – CHC

Leadership Roles

2019-05 – Present	Volunteering – Member of Young Global Entrepreneurs
2019-11	IBM Quantum Computing Summer School
2017-10 – 2018-10	ABSIP Investment Society: Promoting membership – Wits
2014-01 – 2014-11	First Aid: Captain – CHC
2014-01 – 2014-11	Chess Captain: First team – CHC
2014-01 – 2014-11	Student Representative: Head of House – CHC
2013-06 - 2013-11	Football Captain: Centurion Blues Football Club

Hobbies and Interest Groups

Short-distance track events

Toastmasters

Venture growth seminars

RAIL Labs (Robotics, Autonomous Intelligence and Learning) Group